本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
Akiteru, how long can you stay?
明光いつまでいられるの
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
I have work starting on the 14th,
so I'm heading back to Sendai the day after tomorrow.
１４日から仕事だから明後日には仙台戻るよ
You didn't want to go to Kei's match?
蛍の試合見に行かなくてよかたの
He looked pretty annoyed with me when I said that I might go.
昨日行こうかなて言たらすげぇ嫌な顔されたし
Oh, yeah.
そうだ
Mom, there's something I wanted to ask you about Kei's glasses...
母さん蛍のメガネのさ
ただいま
I'm home.
おかえり試合どうだた
Welcome home.
How was the match?
Okay, I guess. We won.
まあ勝たけど
Nice. What were your opponents like?
相手はどんな
Two meters.
２メトル
Huh?
They had a first-year that was 201 cm tall.
１年で２０１センチがいたよ
Two hundred... And you won?
２００勝たのかよ
I guess he just recently started
playing volleyball or something.
まだバレ始めたばかりみたいだたし
Seriously?
マジかよ
My blocks were completely useless against him, though.
まぁブロクは全然歯が立たなかたけどね
I see...
What?
You only think that's obvious when you lose, don't you?
お前負けて当然て思てるだろ
Huh? Yeah.
I mean, he was two meters tall.
だて２メトルだよ
お前さうちのチムの練習混ざてみない
Why don't you come join my team's practice?
Episode Fourteen:
Growing Fast
All right, start your personal practice now!
おしこから自主練
We now have less than two months
until the qualifier at the end of October.
１０月末の代表決定戦まで２ヶ月切たからな
Work hard on improving individually.
それぞれのレベルアプ心掛けろよ
Yay!
ウェイ
Ka—
Kageyama? What are you doing?
影山くんどうしたの
You could tell it was me?
俺てわかるのか
Yeah...
Damn it!
W-Was that supposed to be a disguise?
ももしかして変装のつもりだた
Um, uh...
ええと
There's a team that we might face during the qualifiers,
代表決定戦で当たるかもしれない相手で
so I wanted to check them out no matter what.
どうしても見ておきたいチムがあて
I see! You're going to record a video of them!
なるほどビデオとか撮るんですな
No. There's an unwritten rule that
you can only record official matches.
いやそういうのは基本公式戦だけつのが暗黙のルルだ
So it's not like anything will happen just because I go watch.
だから見たところでどうなるわけでもないけど
But there's less than two months till the qualifiers since summer break is over...
夏休み終わて代表決定戦まで２ヶ月切たし
I feel like I should definitely check them out.
どうしても見ておかないといけない気がして
Um...
If you don't want to stand out at a school after hours, I think it's best to just wear plain training gear.
どの学校でも放課後に一番目立たないためには
普通の運動部ぽい格好が良いのでは
I see.
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Aoba Jousai
High School
Entrance
Bus Stop
And like...
You're kidding! That cracks me up!
ウソウケる
I go to this school...
俺はここの生徒
俺はここの生徒俺はここの生徒
I go to this school...
Act natural... Natural...
ナチュラルに行けナチュラルに
Okay, we're about to start.
よしじゃあそろそろ始めるよ
We're gonna be swapping members next.
次はメンバ代えてくから
Right!
ウィス
ナイサ山口いい感じだぞ
Nice serve, Yamaguchi! It's looking good!
Do you think you could stop Ushiwaka?
なあ月島だたらウシワカ止められるか
Of course not.
無理でしょ
He's the ace of one of the best three teams in the country, so I only could by pure luck.
全国トプ３のエスなんてマグレならまだしも
We can't beat Shiratorizawa if no one can stop him!
でも誰かがウシワカ止めなきゃ白鳥沢倒せない
That's our jobs as middle blockers!
俺達ミドルブロカじゃん
You're already worried about
the best team in the prefecture?
もう県トプのこと考えてんの随分余裕だね
Someone's confident.
One way or the other,
どちみち
we have to beat everyone, so it still matters.
全部倒さなきゃいけないんだから同じだ
You piss me off.
なんか腹立つ
Why?!
なんでだよ
If you can't do it,
月島で無理なら
I'll have to do it myself!
俺がやてやる
Saying you'll do it is one thing,
自分で言うのはともかく
but it really pisses me off when a person goes around telling other people they can't.
他人に「無理」て言われると腹立つよね
Huh?
Especially when that "person" is you.
君はとくに
You pushed my diarrhea pressure point!
下痢ツボ押したな月島このヤロウ
Damn you, Tsukishima!
I'm leaving.
帰る
Hello? It's me.
もしもし蛍だけど
I'm heading over.
今日行くから
Ow!
Sorry!
すまん
He lives!
影山生還どうだたよ
How was it?
I...
俺は
I may never be able to defeat Oikawa.
俺は一生及川さんに勝てないかもしれない
What are you talking about? Stop joking around!
何言てんだふざけんな
Did something happen?!
何見たんだ
I think Seijou was playing a practice match
against a college that some of their alumni attend.
青城は多分ОＢのいる大学と練習試合やてた
When I got there, they were on a break,
俺が行た時には一区切りついてて
and during that break, a different type of match with swapped team members started up.
休憩中にメンバを代えた違う試合が始また
I'm Oikawa. I look forward to playing with you!
及川ですよろしくお願いします
Oikawa joined the college team as their setter.
大学生の中に及川さんがセタとして一人で入た
It didn't look like he knew any of them.
初めて会た人も多いみたいだた
That's Seijou's captain, right?
あれが青城の主将だろ
He's pretty gaudy.
なんかチャラいな
However,
でもほんの数プレで
after just a few plays,
Oikawa had completely blended into the team.
及川さんは完全にチムに溶け込んだ
Even I could tell how lively the spikers felt.
スパイカが生き生きしてるのが俺にもわかた
The way he can draw out 100% of anyone's potential...
誰からもどんな奴からも１００％を引き出すなんて
There's no guarantee that'll happen even if you dedicate tons of time.
たとえ時間をかけたてできるとは限らない
Yet he can do it even if the spiker
hates him or they have weird habits.
でも及川さんはたとえあの人を嫌てる奴とか
すげぇクセのある選手でさえ
I'm sure
きと自在に使いこなす
he could command them at will.
No matter where he is, Oikawa is a setter that can bring out the absolute best in his team.
及川はどこであろうとそのチムの最大値を引き出すセタだ
So you're saying that the Great King freaked you out again?
そのすげぇ大王様に改めてビビちゃたのかよ影山くんは
Yeah, I'm really freaked out.
ああすげぇビビた
Seijou is the team they are now because
they've had Oikawa for the last three years,
その及川さんの三年間全部詰め込んでんのが今の青城で
and spring nationals is our one and only chance to go up against them.
春高はそれと戦える唯一のチャンスだ
We're gonna beat them together, as a team.
チムとして絶対勝つ
Defeat the Great King!
打倒大王様
俺のセリフだバカヤロウ
That's my line, dumbass!
Achoo!
I just got the chills...
悪寒
If you catch a cold, I'm gonna punch you!
風邪なんか引いたらブ飛ばすからな
Have you no mercy?!
それは散々すぎる
Two blockers!
２枚
All right!
よしゃぁ
Adults really are stronger.
やぱ社会人パワが違う
What the hell? You're such a twig!
なんだなんだ
ヒョロちいなちゃんと飯食てんのか
You eating properly?
Can I go home now?
もう帰ていいかな
Come on, Akaizawa. Give it some time.
まあまあ赤井沢さん見ててくださいよ
My little brother will completely shut you down sooner or later.
今にドシャト決めてみせますからうちの弟
There's no way I'd ever lose to
such a wimpy little high schooler!
こんな細こい高校生に負ける俺じゃねぇよ
He loves riling people up. Don't hold it against him.
煽るの大好きな人なんだ許して
Do you think you could stop Ushiwaka?
なあ月島だたらウシワカ止められるか
You only think that's obvious when you lose, don't you?
お前負けて当然と思てるだろ
Maybe that's because you suck at it?
それはさ下手くそだからじゃない
Tch.
Um...
Is there a way to stop an opponent's spike
高さでもパワでも
when they're taller or stronger than you?
自分より圧倒的に上の相手のスパイクを
止める方法はあるんですか
Aoba Jousai Private High School
Hey!
Don't just show up for the first time in forever and act like nothing happened!
久々に来たんならまともに挨拶くらいしろよ
Now, now. Calm down, Yahaba.
まあまあまあ矢巾落ち着いて
Oikawa.
及川さん
It's been a while.
久しぶり待てたよ
I've been waiting for you!
Welcome back, Mad Dog.
おかえり狂犬ちゃん
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
So, who's this "Mad Dog" guy?
誰ですか狂犬て
A second-year named Kyoutani Kentarou.
２年の京谷賢太郎
狂犬は及川さんが勝手にあだ名つけた
"Mad Dog" is a nickname that Oikawa came up with.
He was pretty famous back in junior high, right?
中学ん時結構有名だただろ
Oh, yeah. I remember.
いました確かに
南三中あの代だけ強かたんですよね
South Third Junior High was
really good for just that one year.
Izumitate                South Third
あいつ協調性とか皆無だけど
He refuses to cooperate even a little,
but his actual skill is miles better than anyone else in our grade.
実力は俺達の学年ではズバ抜けててさ
入部早々練習試合に出るチャンスがあたんだけど
Right after joining the team,
he had a chance to play in a practice match,
いきなり当時の３年と衝突してさ
but he immediately started duking it out with the third-years.
The problem was more how he said it than what he said.
言うことはともかく言い方がな
The set is too far from the net, so it's hard to hit it!
ネトからトス離れすぎて打ち辛えすよ
今のフォロできたべや下手くそ
You could've dug it out after the block! You suck!
His attitude toward the third-years didn't change,
その後も当時の３年とは険悪だし
and he eventually stopped showing up.
そのうち来なくなたんだよ
What the hell?
何だよまだ３年いんのかよ
There are still third-years around?
I figured they'd be gone by now
after losing in the interhigh prelims.
インタハイ予選で負けてもう引退したかと思たのに
You're as amusing as ever, Mad Dog.
相変わらず狂犬ちゃんは面白い
変な呼び方しないでほしいんすけど
I wish you'd stop calling me by that weird nickname.
"Ah, I'm so happy I got to play on the team while Oikawa was still here."
「及川さんがいる代に同じチムでプレできてよかた」
That's how I'll make you feel.
て思えるようにしてあげるね
Is he instinctively being wary of Oikawa?
本能で及川さんを警戒している
Nekoma
Metropolitan
High School
So, with the prefectural qualifier in October,
１０月の代表決定戦までの間関東へ練習試合に来られるのは
counting this trip, we'll only be able to go Kanto for practices matches two more times.
今回も含め都合２回ほどです
Let's make the best of this opportunity.
貴重なチャンス有意義に使いましょう
Yes, sir!
Hey, Tsukki!
ヘイツキ
Block some balls for me! Hey, hey, hey!
早速ブロク跳んでくれヘイヘイヘイ
Hey!
チワス
This episode is titled, "Bokuto is Rejected by First-Years From Another School."
木兎他校の１年に引かれるの巻
Okay. Thanks for working with me.
はいお願いします
What?!
自分で頼んどいて何びくりしてるんですか
Why are you so surprised when you're the one who asked him?
Is there a way to stop an opponent's spike
高さでもパワでも
自分より圧倒的に上の相手のスパイクを
when they're taller or stronger than you?
止める方法はあるんですか
ああブロクで一番重要なことて何だと思う
What do you think is most important when blocking?
Height?
高さですか
タイミングだ
It's timing.
極端の話最低限手のひらがネトから出ていれば
To put it simply, if they can get their hands above the net,
even a grade schooler could stop one of Tanaka's spikes.
小学生だて田中のスパイクを止められる
What?!
Provided their timing is perfect, that is.
タイミングさえドンピシャであればな
もちろん手の出し方だとか
Of course, how your hands are positioned and where the ball is traveling matter too.
コスを読むとかも重要だけどな
However, even though I can explain it,
I'm not actually good enough to show you.
ただ俺は口では言えるけど
お手本になるほどうまくねぇ
個人のセンスとかブロクの司令塔として身近で優れてるのは
Someone nearby with the ability to do it and who can direct their team's blocks
駒の黒尾あたりかな
would have to be Kuroo from Nekoma.
リエフ
Lev!
Timing...
タイミング
相手が打ち下ろしてくる瞬間に
The moment that the opponent swings their arm down,
the block must be reaching its peak.
ブロクは天辺に差し掛かる
I-It'll get through next time!
つ次はぶち抜きます
Hey, Tsukki!
おいツキいつまで見る戦やてる
How long are you gonna sit on the sidelines?
Sorry.
すみません
Excuse me.
お邪魔します
Shinzen                  Karasuno
All right!
速攻の成功率はまだ７割ほどでしょうか
It appears that the fast attack's success rate is still about 70%.
よしゃあ
Luck's on our side today!
こればかりは反復練習しかねぇな
Nothing's going to fix that except more practice.
Lev! I told you not to block with your arms spread out!
リエフ万歳ブロクすんなつの
The ball's going right between them!
真ん中抜かれてんじゃねぇか
Your arms need to be close enough that the ball won't go through!
腕はギリボルが抜けない幅
はいす
Right!
Karasuno               Neighborhood Assoc.
Karasuno Sports Complex Indoor Gymnasium
Tokyo Training Camp
Qualifier Matches
Karasuno                     Nekoma
Up front!
前前
すまん
Sorry!
Got it!
オライ
Center!
センタ
日向
Hinata!
It's out!
アウト
Karasuno                     Nekoma
クソすんません
Damn it! Sorry about that!
いよいよ油断ならない感じになてきたな
We can't let our guard down around them anymore.
Yeah.
Even in Tokyo, it's cold at night!
東京でも夜は寒いな
That's because you didn't put on a jacket after getting soaked with sweat.
汗冷える前に上着ないから
試合待ち遠しいな
I'm looking forward to the actual matches!
そうだね
Yeah.
I've been thinking that lately...
最近思うよ
Thinking what?
何を
You're fun to play against,
so I'd like to face you in a real match.
翔陽は面白いから
翔陽と練習じゃない試合やてみたいかもて
Huh?
A match where losing means an instant game over.
負けたら即ゲムオバの試合
Let's do it.
やろう
もう一回がない試合
A match with no do-over.
This is our last chance for the
Battle of the Garbage Dumpster.
ゴミ捨て場の決戦
俺たちにはラストチャンスだ
I'll see you at the Tokyo Gymnasium.
東京体育館で会うぞ
Yeah.
Hey, hey, Tsukki.
ヘイヘイツキ
You absolutely have to beat Ushiwaka and come here to Tokyo!
お前ぜてぇウシワカに勝てこいよ
何でですか
Why's that?
I have an overwhelming winning record against you,
だて俺は今ツキに圧勝中だから
so if you score an overwhelming win against Ushiwaka,
ツキがウシワカに圧勝したら
that's an over-overwhelming win against Ushiwaka for me!
俺はウシワカに圧々勝じゃん
Over-overwhelming win!
I'm sorry. I don't quite get what you mean.
すいませんちょと意味が
Then I'll be the best! Hey, hey, hey!
そしたら俺最強ヘイヘイヘイ
It's not that easy.
簡単に言う
Tokyo Training Camp
Qualifier Matches
レフト
Left!
Akaizawa!
赤井沢さん
レシブ乱れて攻撃はレフト一択
The receive went off course,
so the attack can only come from the left.
The set is slightly back from the net.
トスはネトから離れぎみ
赤井沢さんが得意なコス圧倒的にクロス
Akaizawa's best attack is by far the cross-court spike.
相手が打ち下ろしてくる瞬間に
Right as your opponent swings their arm down,
ブロクの完成を持てくる
your block's in position!
Yeah!
Hey! Wrap it up already!
おいもうそろそろ終われ明日に響くぞ
You'll pay for it tomorrow if you don't!
What? Already?
もうですか
I feel like I haven't hit the ball enough yet.
ちょとまだ打ち足りなくて
For crying out loud...
またく
Why don't you save that feeling for tomorrow?
打ち足りない分はさ明日まで取ておけば
I see!
なるほど
Yes, ma'am!
Kageyama, let's race to see who can pick up the most balls!
影山ボルどちが多く拾えるか競争だ
Bring it on!
望むところだ
Good one, Yachi!
谷地さんナイス
All right, let's take down the net.
Tokyo Training Camp
Qualifier Matches
よしネトも外すぞ
Yessir!
ウィス
Qualifier Matches
お来た
We're here!
Back at the Sendai City Gymnasium once again!
仙台市体育館再び
絶対リベンジ
We're gonna get our revenge!
That's a false start, moron!
フライングすんじゃねぇボケェェ
日向と影山は脊髄反射で生きてる感じだね
It sometimes feels like Hinata and Kageyama act entirely on automatic reflexes.
虫みたい
They're like insects.
Huh?
If you're here, then that means...
てことは
メガネちゃん今日こそ番号教えてね
Hey, cutie with the glasses!
Make sure to give me your digits today!
照れちゃうなんて可愛いな
She's so cute when she gets shy.
Hey!
止めなさい
Stop it!
Jeez!
I-I'm terribly sorry about that!
すすみませんでした
あ止また
Oh, they stopped.
Amazing. They're frozen in midair.
空中で固まてるすげぇ
Well, see you in the first round.
じゃ一回戦よろしく
今のはインタハイ予選ベスト４か
So they're...
Jouzenji
Karasuno
the semifinalist from the interhigh prelims.
This goes without saying, but...
当たり前だけど
They're all here.
Shiratorizawa
Ariagawa
Kaji
Hakusuikan
Midorikawa
Mine West
Sakui
Kesenuma West
Jouzenji
Karasuno
Ougi South
Waku South
Shirato
Date Tech
Niiyama Tech
Aoba Jousai
全員来てんだな
ここに
At this gym.
We're gonna beat all of them!
全部倒す
テンション高いな
They sure are hyper.
Thanks to them, I can stay calm.
おかげで冷静になるわ
I know all too well
俺は知ている
トイレは危険人物と遭遇する場所であることを
that the bathroom is where you run into dangerous people.
Carefully... Carefully...
慎重に慎重に
Whatcha doin'?
何してんの
だ大王様と青城のエスの人
Th-The Great King and Seijou's ace!
２メトル倒して来たんだてなさすがだ
I heard you defeated the two-meter tall guy. Well done.
はいいいえ
Yes! No!
Which is it?
どちだよ
Come time for the match, Shorty here is a royal pain,
試合になるとこのチビちゃん本当厄介だから
so why don't we bury him right now before it's too late?
今のうちにどか埋めちゃう
E-Excuse me!
し失礼します
Hey!
Ow!
日向翔陽
Hinata Shouyou...
And Oikawa and Iwaizumi.
と及川岩泉か
何このタイミング
What's with this timing?
知るか
Hell if I know.
お前たちには高校最後の大会か
This is the last tournament of
your high school career, right?
I wish you the best of luck.
健闘を祈る
本当腹立つ
You seriously piss me off.
We're going to go to nationals, so this won't be the last!
全国行くんだから最後じゃねぇんだよ
全国へ行ける代表枠は一つだが
Only one school can represent our prefecture at nationals, you know?
The fact that he's not being sarcastic...
嫌みで言てんじゃねぇのが
余計腹立つ
...is all the more infuriating!
What's going on?
何だ何だ
Whoa! It's Shiratorizawa and Seijou.
白鳥沢と青城
Did we just walk in on a tense situation?
一触即発
Who's the guy in the middle?
真ん中の誰
Hey, it's that guy from Karasuno!
The team who beat the two-meter tall guy!
あれだこの前２メトル倒した烏野烏野の１０番
It's Karasuno's number ten!
Is he trying to pick a fight with Seijou and Shiratorizawa?
あいつ青城と白鳥沢に喧嘩売てんのかすげぇ
Holy crap!
A-Actually, Karasuno will be the team winning this...
か勝つのは烏野で
Well, u-um...
いいええと
I-I'm so sorry!
すすみません
It doesn't matter who we face. We'll gladly take them on.
誰だろうと受けて立つ
O-Oh, hi.
どどうもす
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
ゴゴレツゴレツゴ伊達工
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
Attack! Attack, attack, attack, attack, Seijou!
Rule the Court
Shiratorizawa!
Unstoppable Force
白鳥沢
ゴゴレツゴレツゴ伊達工
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
The Iron Wall of Date
第一試合はＢコト青城
The first match has Seijou on court B
Ａコト白鳥沢か
and Shiratorizawa on court A.
We're up next!
Karasuno                           Jouzenji
次は俺たちの番だ行くぞ
Let's go!
Yessir!
さあここにいる誰よりも遊ぶべ
All right...
We're gonna play more than anyone else here!
Yee-haw!
Huh?
The party team's here.
出たお祭りチム
条善寺
Jouzenji!
Curse that playboy from Jouzenji!
条善寺のナンパヤロウめ
こうなたら警備を２４時間体制に切り替えるぞ
If that's the case, we're gonna prep to be on guard 'round the clock!
わが命に替えても潔子さんを守り通す
We'll put our lives on the line to defend Kiyoko!
Tanaka and Nishinoya are saying something weird again...
また田中と西谷が何か言てるな
Episode Fifteen:
Playground
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュアソビバ
"Playground."